# RANI MARTUPA SIHOMBING

# MAHASISWI

+6282277110353 | ranisihombing1993@gmail.com

Jalan Kediri 49, Madras Hulu, Medan Polonia, North Sumatera

#### SUMMARY

As an informatics engineering student, I have the ability to program and develop websites and web applications. Have good analytical skills in problem solving, I have experience as a project manager in several group projects. Apart from that, I am also a lab assistant for several courses in the Faculty of Science. a computer that supports my abilities

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Story telling	Problem solving		-	Creativity and innovation
Teamwork		-		Strong time-management skills

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### WEB PROGRAMMING PRACTICAL LAB ASSISTANT

(2024 - Present)

Indonesian Methodist University

• teaches about PHP, PBO, the use of if else and others

#### STATISTICS PRACTICAL LAB ASSISTANT

(2023-Present)

Indonesian Methodist University

- Teach students about using SPSS software
- Teaching students about statistics subjects such as data screening, descriptive statistics, normality test, simple sampling, correlation and association, simple and multiple linear regression and other material using SPSS procedures

#### DATABASES SYSTEM PRACTICAL LAB ASISTANT

(2024-Present)

Indonesian Methodist University

- Database introduction
- · Introduction to data types in PHP my admin, primary key, foreign key, data content/length
- · How to create a database, table, field
- · to how to process the database using the command prompt

## WEB DESIGN/UI UX PRACTICAL LAB ASISTANT

(2023-2024)

Indonesian Methodist University

- Teaches students about HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Telling students tricks about Visual Studio Code software

# WEB DEVELOPER

Juni-Juli 2023

Indonesian Methodist University

- Create a simple SIAKAD (Academic System) website using HTML, CSS, PHP and MySql programming languages
- Implementing a login and CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) system on the system

### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

INDONESIAN METHODIST UNIVERSITY Informatics Engineering|IPK:3.82/4.00

(2021-Present)

ASSISTANT LAB (2013-Present)

Indonesian Mehodist University

SMA N 1 LINTONGNIHUTA (2018-2021)

MIPA|North Sumatra Physics Olympiad and sub-district level